[{"id":"6386","question":"<p>How many different words can be formed with letters of the word &lsquo;ALLAHABAD&rsquo; ?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"7500","option2":"7560","option3":"7510","option4":"7580","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"7560","qa_date":"2016-05-07 05:33:59","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>There are 9 letters in the word ALLAHABAD out of which 4 are A&rsquo;s, 2 are is and the rest are all distinct.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>So, the requisite number of words<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">= <sup>9!<\/sup>\/<sub>4!x<\/sub><sub>2!<\/sub>&nbsp;= 7560<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6449","question":"<p>The pilot knew she would be able to see the __________ lights of the city from her cockpit window. But she would not see the fireworks exploded to well come the new year as she would have __________ to cruising altitude.<\/p>\r\n","option1":"few, soared   ","option2":"divine, escalate    ","option3":"glistening, jumped       ","option4":"shining, reached  ","option5":"glittering, climbed","correct_option":"glittering, climbed","qa_date":"2016-05-13 02:17:06","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6369","question":"<p>(A) Proximate (B) Elevated (C) Nimble (D) Agile<\/p>\r\n","option1":"A-B","option2":"B-C","option3":"A-C","option4":"B-D","option5":"C-D","correct_option":"C-D","qa_date":"2016-05-06 11:59:23","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>(A) Proximate __ nearest or next, without anything between a cause and its effect.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;(B)&nbsp; Elevated __ dignified, elated, grand, high, lofty. Noble, raised, sublime<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (C)&nbsp; Nimble __ active, agile, alert, brisk, deft, light-fitted, lively, ready<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;(D) Agile __ active, adroit, brisk, clever, quick, sharp, swift, spry<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<strong>Hence, C-D bear same meaning.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6365","question":"<p>Which of the following sentences should be the <strong>SIXTH (LAST) <\/strong>after rearrangement?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"A","option2":"B","option3":"C","option4":"E","option5":"F","correct_option":"C","qa_date":"2016-05-06 11:53:32","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6453","question":"<p>Find out the appropriate word in&nbsp;<strong><u>(2)<\/u>&nbsp;<\/strong>?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"renamed   ","option2":"emerged","option3":"appointed","option4":"entrusted","option5":"visited ","correct_option":"emerged","qa_date":"2016-05-13 02:38:11","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6372","question":"<p>(A) Asinine (B) Furious (C) Fortunate (D) Ridiculous<\/p>\r\n","option1":"A-D","option2":"A-B","option3":"A-C","option4":"B-C","option5":"B-D","correct_option":"A-D","qa_date":"2016-05-06 12:11:41","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<ol style=\"list-style-type:upper-alpha\">\r\n\t<li style=\"margin-left: 0.75in;\">(A)Asinine __of or like an ass, idiotic<\/li>\r\n\t<li>Furious + angry, boiling, enraged, fierce, furring, gives, mad, railing, violent, stormy,<\/li>\r\n\t<li>Fortunate __ Advantageous, blessed, bright, lucky, happy, successful, felicitous, importunate<\/li>\r\n\t<li>Ridiculous __ absurd, comical, derisory, farcical, foolish, funny, stupid, ludicrous<\/li>\r\n<\/ol>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <strong>Hence, A-D bear same meaning.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6460","question":"<p>Why was the author two feet shorter when he woke up?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Because he was transformed into a duck.","option2":"Because the cat had jumped on him.","option3":"Because he was transformed into a telephone.","option4":"Because he had not made the machine correctly.","option5":"None of these         ","correct_option":"Because he was transformed into a duck.","qa_date":"2016-05-18 08:47:09","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Refer to the first half of the fourth paragraph.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6371","question":"<p>(A) Limpid (B) Luscious (C) Acrid (D) Benign<\/p>\r\n","option1":"A-B","option2":"B-C","option3":"C-D","option4":"B-D ","option5":"A-C","correct_option":"B-C","qa_date":"2016-05-06 12:09:07","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<ol style=\"list-style-type:upper-alpha\">\r\n\t<li style=\"margin-left: 0.75in;\">(A)Limpid __ bright, bright, clear, comprehensible, crystal-clear, glassy, intelligible, pure<\/li>\r\n\t<li>Luscious__ appetizing, delicious, desirable, juicy, savory, sweet, tasty<\/li>\r\n\t<li>Acrid__ acid, acrimonious, bitter, sharp, burning, pungent, sarcastic<\/li>\r\n\t<li>Benign __ amiable, benevolent, friendly, genial, gentle, good, gracious<\/li>\r\n<\/ol>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <strong>Hence, B-D bear same meaning.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6412","question":"<p>What would be the simple interest obtained on an amount of \u00e2\u201a\u00b9 3.850 at the rate of&nbsp; 4&nbsp; p.c.p.a&nbsp;&nbsp; after&nbsp; 7 years?&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"\u00e2\u201a\u00b9 1,285             ","option2":"\u00e2\u201a\u00b9 1,078            ","option3":"\u00e2\u201a\u00b9  1.146         ","option4":"\u00e2\u201a\u00b9 1.020       ","option5":"None of these        ","correct_option":"\u00e2\u201a\u00b9 1,078            ","qa_date":"2016-05-10 00:53:58","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p><span style=\"color:rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family:arial,sans-serif; font-size:10pt\">Required simple interest = <\/span><span style=\"font-size:14px\"><sup><span style=\"color:rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family:arial,sans-serif\">3850&times;4&times;7<\/span><\/sup><span style=\"color:rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family:arial,sans-serif\">\/<\/span><\/span><span style=\"font-size:12px\"><span style=\"color:rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family:arial,sans-serif\"><sub>100<\/sub><\/span><\/span><span style=\"color:rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family:arial,sans-serif; font-size:10pt\"><span style=\"font-size:12px\"> <\/span>= Rs. 1078.<\/span><\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6441","question":"<p>Which of the following should be the&nbsp;<strong>SECOND<\/strong>&nbsp;sentence after rearrangement?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"F","option2":"D","option3":"C","option4":"E","option5":"A","correct_option":"E","qa_date":"2016-05-13 02:08:58","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6437","question":"<p>Habit of (1)\/ regular saving (2)\/ helps us (3)\/ during bad times. (4)\/ No error (5)<\/p>\r\n","option1":"1","option2":"2","option3":"3","option4":"4","option5":"5","correct_option":"1","qa_date":"2016-05-13 01:47:35","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>&lsquo;A habit of\/ The habit of is the correct usage<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6393","question":"<p><strong>Directions<\/strong>: &nbsp;What should come in the place of question mark(?) in the following questions?<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Seats of Maths, Physics and Biology are in the ratio of 5 : 7 : 8 respectively. There is proposal to increase these seats by 40%, 50% and 75% respectively. What will be the respect ratio of increased seats?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"2 : 3 : 4","option2":"6 : 7 : 8","option3":"6 : 8 : 9","option4":"Cannot be determined  ","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"2 : 3 : 4","qa_date":"2016-05-07 06:10:11","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p style=\"margin-left:54pt\">Let the initial seats for Math , Physics and Biology be 5x, 7x and 8x respectively.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:54pt\">Now , new seats for Maths&nbsp;=&nbsp;<sup>5x&times;140<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>100<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:54pt\">For Physics =&nbsp;<sup>7x150<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>100<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:54pt\">And for Biology =&nbsp;<sup>8x&times;175<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>100<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:54pt\">Required ratio =&nbsp;<sup>5x&times;140<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>100<\/sub>&nbsp;:&nbsp;<sup>7x&times;150<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>100<\/sub>&nbsp;:&nbsp;<sup>8x&times;175<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>100<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:54pt\">= 5 &times; 140 : 7 &times; 150 : 8 &times; 175<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:54pt\">= 2:3:4<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6461","question":"<p>Who does the term &lsquo;the brute&rsquo; used in the passage refer to?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"The author          ","option2":"The toaster          ","option3":"The machine        ","option4":"The clerk        ","option5":"None of these         ","correct_option":"The author          ","qa_date":"2016-05-18 08:47:09","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6464","question":"<p><strong>Directions<\/strong>: &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Choose the word which is <strong>most similar<\/strong> in meaning to the word printed in bold as used in the passage.&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>FLINGING<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Touching","option2":"holding","option3":"bending","option4":"feeling ","option5":"throwing ","correct_option":"throwing ","qa_date":"2016-05-17 23:22:22","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>In the passage &lsquo;flinging&rsquo; means &lsquo;throwing&rsquo;.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6396","question":"<p>What would be the simple interest obtained on an amount of \u00e2\u201a\u00b9 3.850 at the rate of&nbsp; 4&nbsp; p.c.p.a&nbsp;&nbsp; after&nbsp; 7 years?&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"\u00e2\u201a\u00b9 1,285             ","option2":"\u00e2\u201a\u00b9 1,078            ","option3":"\u00e2\u201a\u00b9  1.146         ","option4":"\u00e2\u201a\u00b9 1.020       ","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"\u00e2\u201a\u00b9 1,078            ","qa_date":"2016-05-09 03:51:24","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p><span style=\"font-size:12px\"><span style=\"color:rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family:arial,sans-serif\">Required simple interest = <\/span><sup><span style=\"color:rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family:arial,sans-serif\">3850&times;4&times;7<\/span><\/sup><span style=\"color:rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family:arial,sans-serif\">\/<sub>100<\/sub><\/span><span style=\"color:rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family:arial,sans-serif\"> = Rs. 1078.<\/span><\/span><\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6378","question":"<p>(21.98)<sup>2<\/sup> &ndash; (25.02)<sup>2<\/sup> + (13.03)<sup>2<\/sup> = ?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"25","option2":"120","option3":"10","option4":"65","option5":"140","correct_option":"25","qa_date":"2016-05-07 05:12:09","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">? &nbsp;(22)<sup>2 <\/sup>&ndash; (25)<sup>2<\/sup> + (13)<sup>2<\/sup><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">&nbsp;484 &ndash; 625 + 169 &nbsp;28<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">Required answer = 25&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6436","question":"<p>Just before the demonstration started (1)\/ the police arrive at the site (2)\/ as if they had (3)\/ received information. (4) \/ No error. (5)<\/p>\r\n","option1":"1","option2":"2","option3":"3","option4":"4","option5":"5","correct_option":"2","qa_date":"2016-05-13 01:47:35","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>The sentences shows past event. Hence, &lsquo;the police arrived at the site&rsquo; should be used in place of &lsquo;the police arrive at the site&rsquo;.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6446","question":"<p>Much of the ________ that cricket has is due to the fact it is a ________ sport.<\/p>\r\n","option1":"allure, lucrative   ","option2":"criticism, controversial    ","option3":"attraction, unpopular    ","option4":"flak, great ","option5":"comments, unusual","correct_option":"allure, lucrative   ","qa_date":"2016-05-13 02:17:06","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6435","question":"<p>Although he was expected (1)\/ to work quite hard (2)\/ he could not do so (3) \/ owning to this prolonged illness. (4)\/ No error (5)<\/p>\r\n","option1":"1","option2":"2","option3":"3","option4":"4","option5":"5","correct_option":"5","qa_date":"2016-05-13 01:47:35","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6452","question":"<p>Find out the appropriate word in&nbsp;<strong><u>(1)<\/u>&nbsp;<\/strong>?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"resistant  ","option2":"subservient","option3":"immune","option4":"cordial","option5":"indifference ","correct_option":"resistant  ","qa_date":"2016-05-13 02:38:11","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6434","question":"<p>Our customers are always visit (1)\/ our branches too (2)\/ discuss their problems (3)\/with our staff. (4)\/No error (5)<\/p>\r\n","option1":"1","option2":"2","option3":"3","option4":"4","option5":"5","correct_option":"1","qa_date":"2016-05-13 01:47:35","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>For showing habitual truth, it is proper to use Simple Present Tense. Hence, &lsquo;our customers are always visit&rsquo; should be replaced by &lsquo;our customers always visit&rsquo;.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6384","question":"<p>435&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 354&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 282&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 219&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 165&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (?)&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"103","option2":"112","option3":"120","option4":"130","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"120","qa_date":"2016-05-07 05:21:19","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>The pattern of the number series is :<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">435 &ndash; 9 &times; 9 = 354<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">354 &ndash; 9 &times; 8 = 282<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">282 &ndash; 9 &times; 7 = 219<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">219 &ndash; 9 &times; 6 = 165<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">165 &ndash; 9 &times; 5 = <strong>[120]&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6370","question":"<p>(A) Notion (B) Symbol (C) Concept (D) message<\/p>\r\n","option1":"A - B ","option2":"B - C ","option3":"A -  C","option4":"C - D","option5":"B - D ","correct_option":"B - D ","qa_date":"2016-05-06 12:05:02","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<ol style=\"list-style-type:upper-alpha\">\r\n\t<li style=\"margin-left: 0.75in;\">(A)Notion __ apprehension, belief, concept, fancy, image, judgment, knowledge<\/li>\r\n\t<li>Symbol __ badge, emblem, image, loge, re3presentation sign, token, type<\/li>\r\n\t<li>Concept __ abstraction conception, construct, idea, image, type, view<\/li>\r\n\t<li>Massage __ rubbing, kneading, kneading, manipulation, rap __down<\/li>\r\n<\/ol>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<strong>Hence, B-D bear same meaning.&nbsp;<\/strong>VVVV<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6418","question":"<p>The total number of students in a school is 7,064.If the number of girls in the school is 3,946 then what is the respective ratio of the total number of boys to the total number of girls in the school?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"1559:1973         ","option2":"1981:1551         ","option3":"1973:1559          ","option4":"1551:1981       ","option5":"None of these        ","correct_option":"1559:1973         ","qa_date":"2016-05-10 01:04:01","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>The total number of boys in the school = 7064 &ndash; 3946 = 3118.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; Respective ratio of boys and girls = 3118:3946 = 1559:1973.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6399","question":"<p>Two-fifty of one number is equal to one-third of another number. What is the respective ratio of the first number to the second number?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"6:5          ","option2":"7:8            ","option3":"5:6           ","option4":"8:7        ","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"5:6           ","qa_date":"2016-05-09 03:51:24","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Let one number is x and another number is y then,<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; x&times;<sup>2<\/sup>\/<sub>7<\/sub> = y&times;<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><sup>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; x<\/sup>\/<sub>y <\/sub>= <sup>5<\/sup>\/<sub>6<\/sub> = 5:6<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6411","question":"<p>How many girls are in course C?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"44","option2":"16","option3":"40","option4":"160","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"16","qa_date":"2016-05-09 04:20:15","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>No. of girls in course C=2% of 800 =16<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6410","question":"<p>For which course is the number of boys the minimum?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"E","option2":"F","option3":"C","option4":"A","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"A","qa_date":"2016-05-09 04:20:15","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6405","question":"<p><span style=\"color:rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family:arial,sans-serif; font-size:10pt\">The of 12 electric toasters and 14 ovens is Rs. 84,126. What is the coast of 18 electric toasters and 21 ovens?<\/span><\/p>\r\n","option1":"Rs. 128,000   ","option2":"Rs. 125,000    ","option3":"Rs. 116,500    ","option4":"Cannot be determined    ","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"None of these       ","qa_date":"2016-05-09 04:00:40","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>The cost of 6 Electric Toasters and 7 ovens&nbsp; = Rs. 84,126\/2<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;= Rs. 42,063.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>The cost of 18 Electric Toasters and 21 ovens&nbsp; = Rs. 42,063&times;3<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;= Rs. 1,26,189.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6401","question":"<p>Trisha invests \u00e2\u201a\u00b9 8.820 which is 24% of her monthly in- come?&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Rs 27,500     ","option2":"Rs 38,450    ","option3":"Rs 29,250  ","option4":"Rs 36,750  ","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"Rs 36,750  ","qa_date":"2016-05-09 03:56:19","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Let her monthly income is Rs. x, then<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; x&times;<sup>24<\/sup>\/<sub>100 <\/sub>= Rs. 8820<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;x = <sup>8820&times;100<\/sup>\/<sub>24<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; x = Rs. 36,750<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6390","question":"<p>Mr. &lsquo;X&rsquo; invested certain amounts in two different schemes &lsquo;A&rsquo; offers simple interest at 12 p. c. a. and Scheme &lsquo;B&rsquo; offers compound interest at 10 p. c. p. a. interest accrued on the amount invested in Scheme A in 2 years was Rs. 3.600 and the total amount invested was Rs. 35.000. What was interest accrued on the amount invested in Scheme &lsquo;B&rsquo;?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Rs. 4,800","option2":"Rs. 4,200","option3":"Rs. 4,000","option4":"Cannot be determined    ","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"Rs. 4,200","qa_date":"2016-05-07 05:59:05","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Let the amount invested in scheme A be Rs. X.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\"><sup>X &times; 12 &times; 2<\/sup> \/ <sub>100<\/sub> = 3600<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">&rarr; x = <sup>3600 &times; 100<\/sup>\/<sub>24 <\/sub>=Rs.15000<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">Total investment =Rs. 35000<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">Amount invested in scheme B<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">=Rs. (35000 &ndash; 15000)<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">=Rs. 20000<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">C. I. =P [(1 + <sup>R<\/sup>\/<sub>100<\/sub>)<sup>T<\/sup> &ndash; 1 ]<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">=20000 [(1 + <sup>10<\/sup>\/<sub>100<\/sub>)<sup>2<\/sup> &ndash; 1 ]<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">=20000 (1.21 &ndash; 1)<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">=20000 &times; 0.21 = Rs. 4200<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6466","question":"<p><strong>Directions<\/strong>: &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Choose the word which is <strong>most opposite<\/strong> in meaning to the word printed in bold as used in the passage.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>TERRIBLE<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Better  ","option2":"wonderful   ","option3":"extreme ","option4":"awful  ","option5":"fearful","correct_option":"wonderful   ","qa_date":"2016-05-17 23:25:59","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>&lsquo;Wonderful &lsquo;in most opposite in meaning of the world &rsquo;terrible&rsquo; as used in the passage.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6375","question":"<p>9228.789 &ndash; 5021.832 + 1496.989 = ?&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"6500 ","option2":"6000","option3":"6300","option4":"5700","option5":"5100","correct_option":"5700","qa_date":"2016-05-07 05:12:09","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">? = 9230 &ndash; 5022 + 1500 = 5708<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">Required answer = 5700&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6427","question":"<p>Which trend boost capital growth in the modern era?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Conversion of land and labor to private equity.","option2":"Converting manufacturing industries into service sector.","option3":"Generating resources through international trade.","option4":"Promoting information based and software companies.","option5":"None of these        ","correct_option":"Promoting information based and software companies.","qa_date":"2016-05-13 01:40:21","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Promoting information based and software companies.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6462","question":"<p>How did the author manage to call the clerk?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"By dragging the phone towards himself.        ","option2":"By hitting the button on the machine","option3":"By shouting for help         ","option4":"By flinging toast at the phone on the wall and then asking the clerk for help            ","option5":"None of these         ","correct_option":"By dragging the phone towards himself.        ","qa_date":"2016-05-18 08:47:09","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6455","question":"<p>Find out the appropriate word in&nbsp;<strong><u>(4)<\/u>&nbsp;<\/strong>?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"people","option2":"few ","option3":"diplomats  ","option4":"autocrats ","option5":"most","correct_option":"few ","qa_date":"2016-05-13 02:38:11","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6425","question":"<p>The public of which type of companies and preferred by the investors at present?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Services sector companies","option2":"Agro based companies","option3":"Information based companies.","option4":"Companies dealing with financial sector.","option5":"None of these.","correct_option":"Information based companies.","qa_date":"2016-05-13 01:40:21","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Information based companies.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6361","question":"<p>Which of the following is the second digit of the third highest number?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"7","option2":"1","option3":"5","option4":"8","option5":"3","correct_option":"3","qa_date":"2016-05-06 23:38:33","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Third highest number 435 and second digit of that number is 3.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6430","question":"<p><strong>Directions:&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/strong>Choose the word\/group of words which is&nbsp;<strong>most similar&nbsp;<\/strong>in meaning to the word printed in&nbsp;<strong>bold&nbsp;<\/strong>as used in the passage.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>Advent&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n","option1":"Shining  ","option2":"departure  ","option3":"power   ","option4":"force ","option5":"arrival","correct_option":"arrival","qa_date":"2016-05-13 01:40:21","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>The word &lsquo;advent&rsquo; has been used in the sense of word &lsquo;arrival&rsquo;.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6417","question":"<p>Anisha invests \u00e2\u201a\u00b9 8.820 which is 24% of her monthly in- come?&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Rs 27,500     ","option2":"Rs 38,450    ","option3":"Rs 29,250  ","option4":"Rs 36,750  ","option5":"None of  these ","correct_option":"Rs 36,750  ","qa_date":"2016-05-10 01:04:01","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Let her monthly income is Rs. x, then<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; x&times;<sup>24<\/sup>\/<sub>100 <\/sub>= Rs. 8820<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; x = <sup>8820&times;100<\/sup>\/<sub>24<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; x = Rs. 36,750<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6385","question":"<p>4&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 200&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 369&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 513&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 634&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (?)&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"788","option2":"715","option3":"734","option4":"755","option5":"None of these ","correct_option":"734","qa_date":"2016-05-07 05:21:19","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>The pattern of the number series is :<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">4 + 14<sup>2<\/sup> = 4 + 196 = 200<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">200 + 13<sup>2<\/sup> = 200 + 169 = 369<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">369 + 12<sup>2<\/sup> = 369 + 144 = 513<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">531 + 11<sup>2<\/sup> = 513 + 121 = 634<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">634 + 10<sup>2<\/sup> = 634 + 100 = <strong>[734]<\/strong><\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6447","question":"<p>Since foggy weather _________ visibility by several metres, the railways has either partially __________ or diverted some of the trains.<\/p>\r\n","option1":"improves, started      ","option2":"impairs, called off","option3":"hampers, withdrawn","option4":"decrease, stopped     ","option5":"reduces, cancelled","correct_option":"reduces, cancelled","qa_date":"2016-05-13 02:17:06","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6448","question":"<p>The once _________ distinct is gradually being _________ of its green cover.<\/p>\r\n","option1":"remote, eroded     ","option2":"arid, replenished","option3":"beautiful, devoid   ","option4":"picturesque, depleted    ","option5":"lush, rob","correct_option":"picturesque, depleted    ","qa_date":"2016-05-13 02:17:06","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6467","question":"<p><strong>Directions<\/strong>: &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Choose the word which is <strong>most opposite<\/strong> in meaning to the word printed in bold as used in the passage.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>RUDIMENTARY<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Advanced  ","option2":"basic ","option3":"evil","option4":"forward ","option5":"artificial","correct_option":"Advanced  ","qa_date":"2016-05-17 23:28:06","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>&lsquo;Advanced&rsquo; is most opposite in meaning of the world &lsquo;rudimentary &lsquo;as used in the passage.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6404","question":"<p><span style=\"color:rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family:arial,sans-serif; font-size:10pt\">The average age of a man and his son is 48 years. The ratio of their ages is 2:1 respectively. What is son&rsquo;s age.<\/span><\/p>\r\n","option1":"28 years       ","option2":"35 years      ","option3":"24 years       ","option4":"32 years       ","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"32 years       ","qa_date":"2016-05-09 04:00:40","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Let the age of man and his son is 2x and x years respectively then,<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>2x + x = 48&times;2<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>3x = 96<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>x = 32 years.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6450","question":"<p>The New Year has __________ in good news for city hotels as most properties are __________ for the whole month.<\/p>\r\n","option1":"brought, deserted   ","option2":"ushered, packed","option3":"pushed, full      ","option4":"steered, renovating","option5":"escorted, vacant","correct_option":"ushered, packed","qa_date":"2016-05-13 02:17:06","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6416","question":"<p>If the fractions <sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>5<\/sub>,<sup>5<\/sup>\/<sub>7<\/sub>,<sup>11<\/sup>\/<sub>13<\/sub>,<sup>7<\/sup>\/<sub>11<\/sub> and <sup>8<\/sup>\/<sub>9<\/sub> are arranged&nbsp; in ascending&nbsp; order of their values ,which one will be the fourth?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"7\/11      ","option2":"3\/5      ","option3":"11\/13         ","option4":"8\/9      ","option5":"None of these        ","correct_option":"11\/13         ","qa_date":"2016-05-10 00:53:58","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p><sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>5 <\/sub>= 0.60,<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;5\/<sub>7 <\/sub>= 0.71<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; &nbsp;11\/<sub>13 <\/sub>= 0.85<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><sup>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 7<\/sup>\/<sub>11 <\/sub>= 0.64<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp; &nbsp; 8\/<sub>9 <\/sub>= 0.89<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>The ascending order of the fractions <sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>5<\/sub>, <sup>7<\/sup>\/<sub>11, <\/sub><sup>5<\/sup>\/<sub>7, <\/sub><sup>11<\/sup>\/<sub>13, <\/sub><sup>8<\/sup>\/<sub>9.<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Fourth in order = <sup>11<\/sup>\/<sub>13.<\/sub><\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6360","question":"<p>Which of the following is the sum of the first and the second digits of the lowest number?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"10","option2":"12","option3":"7","option4":"13","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"10","qa_date":"2016-05-06 23:38:33","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>The lowest number is 283. The sum of the first and the second digits is 2+8 = 10<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6419","question":"<p>Find the average of the following set of scores.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 216,&nbsp; 463, 154,&nbsp; 605,&nbsp; 446,&nbsp; 336<\/p>\r\n","option1":"387","option2":"370","option3":"379","option4":"380","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"370","qa_date":"2016-05-10 01:04:01","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Required average = <sup>addition of all six numbers<\/sup>\/<sub>6<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; = <sup>2220<\/sup>\/<sub>6<\/sub> = 370.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6428","question":"<p>What is meant by angel investors?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"The investors who fund the project till such time it starts attracting large investment.","option2":"Those people who are committed to develop virtual economy. ","option3":"The investors who invest on behalf of someone else. ","option4":"Those who invest in only companies who have an excellent evaluation","option5":"None of these.","correct_option":"The investors who fund the project till such time it starts attracting large investment.","qa_date":"2016-05-13 01:40:21","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>The investors who fund the project till such time it starts attracting large investment.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6400","question":"<p>If the fractions <sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>5<\/sub>,<sup>5<\/sup>\/<sub>7<\/sub>,<sup>11<\/sup>\/<sub>13<\/sub>,<sup>7<\/sup>\/<sub>11<\/sub> and <sup>8<\/sup>\/<sub>9<\/sub> are arranged&nbsp; in ascending&nbsp; order of their values ,which one will be the fourth?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"7\/11      ","option2":"3\/5      ","option3":"11\/13         ","option4":"8\/9      ","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"11\/13         ","qa_date":"2016-05-09 03:51:24","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p><sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>5 <\/sub>= 0.60,<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><sup>5<\/sup>\/<sub>7 <\/sub>= 0.71<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><sup>11<\/sup>\/<sub>13 <\/sub>= 0.85<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><sup>7<\/sup>\/<sub>11 <\/sub>= 0.64<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><sup>&nbsp;8<\/sup>\/<sub>9 <\/sub>= 0.89<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>The ascending order of the fractions <sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>5<\/sub>, <sup>7<\/sup>\/<sub>11, <\/sub><sup>5<\/sup>\/<sub>7, <\/sub><sup>11<\/sup>\/<sub>13, <\/sub><sup>8<\/sup>\/<sub>9.<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Fourth in order = <sup>11<\/sup>\/<sub>13.<\/sub><\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6438","question":"<p>To know what people react to (1)\/ unforeseen situation (2)\/ is very important (3)\/ to decide our course of action. (4) \/ No error (5)<\/p>\r\n","option1":"1","option2":"2","option3":"3","option4":"4","option5":"5","correct_option":"5","qa_date":"2016-05-13 01:47:35","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6381","question":"<p>7&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 20&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 46&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 98&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 202&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (?)&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"420","option2":"410","option3":"310","option4":"320","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"410","qa_date":"2016-05-07 05:21:19","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>The pattern of the number series is :<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">7 &times; 2 + 6 = 20<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">20 &times; 2 + 6 = 46<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">46 &times; 2 + 6 = 98<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">98 &times; 2 + 6 = 202<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">202 &times; 2 + 6 = 404 + 6 = <strong>[410]<\/strong><\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6379","question":"<p>&radic;2498 &times; &radic;626 &divide; &radic;99 =?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"110","option2":"90","option3":"200","option4":"160","option5":"125","correct_option":"125","qa_date":"2016-05-07 05:12:09","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">? = &radic;2500 &times; &radic;626 &divide; &radic;100<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">&nbsp;50 &times; 25 &times; <sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>10<\/sub> =&nbsp;125&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6408","question":"<p>For which pair of courses is the number of boys the same?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"E & F ","option2":"A & D","option3":"C & F","option4":"B & D","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"C & F","qa_date":"2016-05-09 04:20:15","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>number of boys in course E = 12% of 1200 &ndash; 14%<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">Of 800 = 144 &ndash; 112 =32<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">In course F = 13% of 1200-14%<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">Of 800 = 156 &ndash; 112 = 44<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">In course A = 20% of 1200-30%<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">Of 800 = 340 &ndash; 240= 0<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">In course D = 35% of 1200-30%<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">Of 800 = 420 &ndash; 240 = 180<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">In course C = 5% of 1200-2%<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">Of 800 = 60 &ndash; 16 = 44<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">Obviously pair C and F is our answer.&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6397","question":"<p>In an examination it is required to get 65% of the aggregate marks to pass a student gets 540 marks and is declared failed by 5%. What are the maximum aggregate marks a student can get?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"900","option2":"860","option3":"750","option4":"Cannot be determined         ","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"900","qa_date":"2016-05-09 03:51:24","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>60% marks = 540<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;100% marks = <sup>540&times;100<\/sup>\/<sub>60 <\/sub>= 900<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6358","question":"<p>Which of the following is the difference between the second and third digits of the second lowest number?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"5","option2":"8","option3":"2","option4":"1","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"8","qa_date":"2016-05-06 23:38:33","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>The Second lowest number is 391.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>The difference between the second and third digits = 9 &ndash; 1 = 8.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6431","question":"<p><strong>Directions:&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/strong>Choose the word\/phrase which is&nbsp;<strong>most opposite&nbsp;<\/strong>in meaning to the word printed in&nbsp;<strong>bold&nbsp;<\/strong>as used in the passage.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>Burgeoning&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n","option1":"Growing","option2":"retarding ","option3":"dipping ","option4":"unique","option5":"common","correct_option":"retarding ","qa_date":"2016-05-13 01:40:21","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6454","question":"<p>Find out the appropriate word in&nbsp;<strong><u>(3)<\/u>&nbsp;<\/strong>?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"shirk ","option2":"avoid ","option3":"transfer ","option4":"visualize ","option5":"inherit ","correct_option":"inherit ","qa_date":"2016-05-13 02:38:11","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6421","question":"<p>The of 12 electric toasters and 14 ovens is Rs. 84,126. What is the coast of 18 electric toasters and 21 ovens?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Rs. 128,000   ","option2":"Rs. 125,000    ","option3":"Rs. 116,500    ","option4":"Cannot be determined    ","option5":"None of these        ","correct_option":"None of these        ","qa_date":"2016-05-10 01:04:01","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>The cost of 6 Electric Toasters and 7 ovens&nbsp; = Rs. 84,126\/2<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; = Rs. 42,063.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>The cost of 18 Electric Toasters and 21 ovens&nbsp; = Rs. 42,063&times;3<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;= Rs. 1,26,189.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6443","question":"<p>Which of the following should be the&nbsp;<strong>FIFTH<\/strong>&nbsp;sentence after rearrangement?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"A","option2":"B","option3":"C","option4":"D","option5":"E","correct_option":"C","qa_date":"2016-05-13 02:08:58","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6394","question":"<p>A boat takes 6 hours to travel from place M to N downstream. If the speed of the boat in still water is 4 km\/hr., what is the distance between the two places?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"8 kms.","option2":"12 kms.","option3":"6 kms.","option4":"Cannot be determined    ","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"Cannot be determined    ","qa_date":"2016-05-07 06:11:35","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Total time = 6 hours<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:54pt\">Speed of boat in still water<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:54pt\">= 4 km\/hr<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:54pt\">Let the distance between M and N be D<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:54pt\">And the speed of the stream be x.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:54pt\">D [<sup>1<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>4+x<\/sub>&nbsp;+&nbsp;<sup>1<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>4 - x<\/sub>] = 6 D [<sup>4-x+4+x<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>(x+x)(4-x)<\/sub>]<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:54pt\">= 6 D [<sup>8<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>42- x2<\/sub>]&nbsp;<sup>8D<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>16-x2<\/sub>&nbsp;= 6 D<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:54pt\">=&nbsp;<sup>16<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>8<\/sub>(16-x2) =&nbsp;<sup>3<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>4<\/sub>(16-x2)<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Since the speed of stream (x) is not given , the distance (D) cannot be determined<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6357","question":"<p>If the positions of the first and the second digits within each number are interchanged. Which of the following will be the second digit of the highest number?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"8","option2":"3","option3":"4","option4":"6","option5":"2","correct_option":"3","qa_date":"2016-05-06 23:38:33","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>826&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 391&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 435&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 678&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 283<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>286&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 931&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 345&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 768&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 823<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Here the highest number is 931.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Its second digit is 3.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6426","question":"<p>What impact of economy has been envisaged owing to rise in net enterprise?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"The venture capitalists have started financing the projects even at the planning stage.","option2":"The economic planning will no more be realistic now.","option3":"The funding of unplanned projects have increased.","option4":"Virtual economy has necessitated the source of funds from abroad.","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"The venture capitalists have started financing the projects even at the planning stage.","qa_date":"2016-05-13 01:40:21","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>The venture capitalists have started financing the projects even at the planning stage.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6463","question":"<p><strong>Directions<\/strong>: &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Choose the word which is <strong>most similar<\/strong> in meaning to the word printed in bold as used in the passage.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>SYNTHETIC<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Loud  ","option2":"clothed","option3":"real","option4":"electron ","option5":"soft","correct_option":"clothed","qa_date":"2016-05-17 23:20:11","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>In the passage &lsquo;synthetic &lsquo;means &lsquo;clothed&rsquo;.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6432","question":"<p><strong>Directions:&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/strong>Choose the word\/phrase which is&nbsp;<strong>most opposite&nbsp;<\/strong>in meaning to the word printed in&nbsp;<strong>bold&nbsp;<\/strong>as used in the passage.&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>Stagnating&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n","option1":"Developing ","option2":"redundant   ","option3":"over working","option4":"fixed ","option5":"stationery ","correct_option":"Developing ","qa_date":"2016-05-13 01:40:21","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6444","question":"<p>Which of the following should be the&nbsp;<strong>SIXTH (last)<\/strong>&nbsp;sentence after rearrangement?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"A","option2":"B","option3":"C","option4":"D","option5":"E","correct_option":"C","qa_date":"2016-05-13 02:08:58","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6363","question":"<p>Which of the following sentences should be the <strong>FIRST <\/strong>after rearrangement?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"A","option2":"B","option3":"C","option4":"D","option5":"E","correct_option":"B","qa_date":"2016-05-06 11:52:29","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6383","question":"<p>27&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 38&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 71&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 126&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 203&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (?)&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"212","option2":"202","option3":"301","option4":"312","option5":"None of these      ","correct_option":"None of these      ","qa_date":"2016-05-07 05:21:19","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">The pattern of the number series is :<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">27 + 11 = 38<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">38 + 33 = 71<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">71 + 55 = 126<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">126 + 77 = 203<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">203 + 99 = <strong>[302]&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6423","question":"<p>Which of the following has been rated as most crucial in agro- based economy?<\/p>\r\n\r\n<ol style=\"list-style-type:upper-alpha\">\r\n\t<li>Capital, steamboat and trains<\/li>\r\n\t<li>Technological innovations like plough, etc.<\/li>\r\n\t<li>Labour and land.<\/li>\r\n<\/ol>\r\n","option1":"Only A and B","option2":"Only C","option3":"Only B","option4":"Only A ","option5":"None of theseOnly C","correct_option":"Only C","qa_date":"2016-05-13 01:40:21","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Only C<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6389","question":"<p>4 boys and three girls are to be seated in a row in such a way that no two boys sit adjacent to each other.&nbsp; In how many different ways can it be done?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"5040","option2":"30","option3":"144","option4":"72","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"144","qa_date":"2016-05-07 05:59:05","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>3 girls can be seated in a row in 3 &nbsp;ways.&nbsp; Now, in the 4 gaps 4 boys can be seated in 4 &nbsp;ways Hence, the number of ways in which no two boys sit adjacent to each other<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">= 3&nbsp;&times; 4&nbsp;= 6 &times; 24 = 144<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6440","question":"<p>Which of the following should be the&nbsp;<strong>FIRST<\/strong>&nbsp;sentence after rearrangement?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"A","option2":"B","option3":"C","option4":"D","option5":"E","correct_option":"B","qa_date":"2016-05-13 02:08:58","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6409","question":"<p>For course E, the number of girls is how much per cent more than the boys for course E?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"250","option2":"350","option3":"150","option4":"80","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"250","qa_date":"2016-05-09 04:20:15","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Four Course E,<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>No. of girls = 14% of 800=12<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>No. of boys = 32<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Required percentage =<sup>80<\/sup>\/<sub>32<\/sub> &times;100 = 250<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6359","question":"<p>Which of the following is the third digit of the second highest number?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"7","option2":"1","option3":"5","option4":"8","option5":"3","correct_option":"8","qa_date":"2016-05-06 23:38:33","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>The second highest number is 678 whose third digit is 8.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6392","question":"<p>A shopkeeper sells milk which contains 5% water. What quantity of pure milk should be added to 2 litres of milk (containing 5% water) so that proportion of water becomes 4%?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"100 ml ","option2":"250 ml ","option3":"400 ml ","option4":"350 ml ","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"None of these       ","qa_date":"2016-05-07 06:08:02","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6456","question":"<p>Find out the appropriate word in&nbsp;<strong><u>(5)<\/u>&nbsp;<\/strong>?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"credibility","option2":"difficult","option3":"majority","option4":"power ","option5":"enthusiasm  ","correct_option":"credibility","qa_date":"2016-05-13 02:38:11","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6458","question":"<p>Which of the following is not true in the context of the passage?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"The clerk was part of the experiment right from the start ","option2":"The clerk managed to bring the author back to his original state.","option3":"The experiment did not go completely as planned.","option4":"The author\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s mind was transferred into the toaster.","option5":"All of the above are true.","correct_option":"The clerk was part of the experiment right from the start ","qa_date":"2016-05-18 08:47:09","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>The answer can be easily inferred from the passage.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6414","question":"<p>What would be the area of a circle whose diameter is 98 cm.?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"7584 sq cm    ","option2":"7124 sq cm           ","option3":"7546 sq cm         ","option4":"7456 sq cm    ","option5":"None of these        ","correct_option":"7546 sq cm         ","qa_date":"2016-05-10 00:53:58","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Required area = <sup>22<\/sup>\/<sub>7<\/sub>&times;<sup>98<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>&times;<sup>98<\/sup>\/<sub>2 <\/sub>Sq. cm.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; = 11&times;7&times;98 sq. cm.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; = 7546 sq. cm.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6373","question":"<p>(A) Companion (B) Amateur (C) Adept (D) Adherent<\/p>\r\n","option1":"B-C","option2":"B-D","option3":"C-D","option4":"A-B","option5":"A-D","correct_option":"A-D","qa_date":"2016-05-06 12:15:41","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p style=\"margin-left: 0.75in;\">(A)Companion __ accomplice, aide, ally, assistant, associate fellow, mate, partnerV<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>(B) Amateur - buff, dabbler, dilettante, &nbsp;ham, layman, non-professional,<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>(C) Adept __ able, accomplished, adroit, versed, skilled, proficient, practiced nimble.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>(D) Adherent __ admirer, advocate, devotee, disciple, fan, follower, supporter<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; <strong>Hence, A-D bear same meaning.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6442","question":"<p>Which of the following should be the&nbsp;<strong>THIRD<\/strong>&nbsp;sentence after rearrangement?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"A","option2":"B","option3":"C","option4":"D","option5":"E","correct_option":"A","qa_date":"2016-05-13 02:08:58","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6402","question":"<p>The total number of students in a school is 7,064.If the number of girls in the school is 3,946 then what is the respective ratio of the&nbsp; total number of boys to the total number of girls in the school?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"1559:1973         ","option2":"1981:1551         ","option3":"1973:1559          ","option4":"1551:1981       ","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"1559:1973         ","qa_date":"2016-05-09 03:56:19","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>The total number of boys in the school = 7064 &ndash; 3946 = 3118.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;Respective ratio of boys and girls = 3118:3946 = 1559:1973.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6398","question":"<p>What would be the area of a circle whose diameter is 98 cm.?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"7584 sq cm    ","option2":"7124 sq cm           ","option3":"7546 sq cm         ","option4":"7456 sq cm    ","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"7546 sq cm         ","qa_date":"2016-05-09 03:51:24","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Required area = <sup>22<\/sup>\/<sub>7<\/sub>&times;<sup>98<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>&times;<sup>98<\/sup>\/<sub>2 <\/sub>Sq. cm.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; = 11&times;7&times;98 sq. cm.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; = 7546 sq. cm.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6395","question":"<p>By selling article for Rs. 240 a man incurs a loss of 10%. At what price should he sell it. so that he makes a profit of 20%?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Rs. 264   ","option2":"Rs. 288   ","option3":"Rs. 300","option4":"Rs. 320 ","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"Rs. 320 ","qa_date":"2016-05-07 06:13:50","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>90% of C.P. = Rs. 240<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>C.P. = Rs.&nbsp;<sup>240 &times; 100<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>90<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>New S.P = 120% of C.P.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= Rs. 240 &times;<sup>100<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>90<\/sub>&times;<sup>120<\/sup>&frasl;<sub>100<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>= Rs. 320<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6377","question":"<p>29.8% of 260 + 60.01% of 510 &ndash; 103.57 = ?&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"450","option2":"320","option3":"210","option4":"280","option5":"350","correct_option":"280","qa_date":"2016-05-07 05:12:09","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">? <sup>260 &times; 30<\/sup>\/<sub>100 <\/sub>+ <sup>510 &times; 60<\/sup>\/<sub>100<\/sub> &ndash; 100<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">&nbsp;78 + 306 &ndash; 100 284<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">Required answer = 280&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6415","question":"<p>Two-fifty of one number is equal to one-third of another number. What is the respective ratio of the first number to the second number?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"6:5          ","option2":"7:8            ","option3":"5:6           ","option4":"8:7        ","option5":"None of these        ","correct_option":"5:6           ","qa_date":"2016-05-10 00:53:58","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Let one number is x and another number is y then,<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;x&times;<sup>2<\/sup>\/<sub>7<\/sub> = y&times;<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;<sup>x<\/sup>\/<sub>y <\/sub>= <sup>5<\/sup>\/<sub>6<\/sub> = 5:6<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6424","question":"<p>How did service economy evolve into a global economy?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"The wealth gained through services exceeded the gain through manufacture.","option2":"The services started flowing across boards.","option3":"The labor started producing goods for mass market.","option4":"The trade for services and goods crossed the international borders","option5":"None of these","correct_option":"The trade for services and goods crossed the international borders","qa_date":"2016-05-13 01:40:21","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>The trade for services and goods crossed an international borders.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6420","question":"<p><span style=\"color:rgb(34, 34, 34); font-family:arial,sans-serif; font-size:10pt\">The average age of a man and his son is 48 years. The ratio of their ages is 2:1 respectively. What is son&rsquo;s age.<\/span><\/p>\r\n","option1":"28 years       ","option2":"35 years      ","option3":"24 years       ","option4":"32 years       ","option5":"None of these        ","correct_option":"32 years       ","qa_date":"2016-05-10 01:04:01","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Let the age of man and his son is 2x and x years respectively then,<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>2x + x = 48&times;2<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>3x = 96<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>x = 32 years.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6459","question":"<p>What was the author making?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"He was making a toaster which could talk.","option2":"He was making a machine which could control animal behavior.","option3":"He was making a machine which could convert itself into toaster.","option4":"He was making a machine which could exchange the minds of two entities.","option5":"None of these        ","correct_option":"He was making a machine which could exchange the minds of two entities.","qa_date":"2016-05-18 08:47:09","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Refer to the second half of the second paragraph.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6429","question":"<p><strong>Directions:&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/strong>Choose the word\/group of words which is&nbsp;<strong>most similar&nbsp;<\/strong>in meaning to the word printed in&nbsp;<strong>bold&nbsp;<\/strong>as used in the passage.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>Access&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n","option1":"Reach  ","option2":"loan ","option3":"help  ","option4":"advantage ","option5":"utility","correct_option":"Reach  ","qa_date":"2016-05-13 01:40:21","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6364","question":"<p>Which of the following sentences should be the <strong>THIRD <\/strong>after rearrangement?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"A","option2":"E","option3":"D","option4":"F","option5":"C","correct_option":"A","qa_date":"2016-05-07 00:06:43","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6355","question":"<p><strong>Statements:<\/strong><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Some rocks are toys.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>Some toys are flowers.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>All flowers are pots.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p><strong>Conclusions: &nbsp;&nbsp;I.&nbsp; <\/strong>Some pots are rocks.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;<strong>II.<\/strong> Some pots are toys.<\/p>\r\n","option1":"1","option2":"2","option3":"3","option4":"4","option5":"5","correct_option":"2","qa_date":"2016-05-06 23:32:55","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6465","question":"<p><strong>Directions<\/strong>: &nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Choose the word which is <strong>most similar<\/strong> in meaning to the word printed in bold as used in the passage.&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>INITIATED<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Withstand  ","option2":"worked ","option3":"stopped  ","option4":"started ","option5":"culminate","correct_option":"started ","qa_date":"2016-05-17 23:24:10","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>In the passage &lsquo;initiated&rsquo; means &lsquo;started&rsquo;.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6407","question":"<p>For course D what is the respect-five ratio of boys and girls?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"3 : 4","option2":"4 : 5","option3":"3 : 5 ","option4":"5 : 6 ","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"3 : 4","qa_date":"2016-05-09 04:20:15","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>For Course D<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">No. of girls = 30% of 800 = <sup>30 &times;800<\/sup>\/<sub>100<\/sub> = 240<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">No. of students = &times; <sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>100<\/sub> &times; 1200 = 420<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">No. of boys = 420 &ndash; 240 = 180<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">Required ratio = 180 : 240 = 3:4<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6367","question":"<p>Which of the following sentences should be the <strong>FIFTH<\/strong> after rearrangement?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"D","option2":"B","option3":"C","option4":"E","option5":"F","correct_option":"F","qa_date":"2016-05-06 11:56:09","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""},{"id":"6413","question":"<p>In an examination it is required to get 65% of the aggregate marks to pass a student gets 540 marks and is declared failed by 5%. What are the maximum aggregate marks a student can get?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"900","option2":"860","option3":" 750","option4":"Cannot be determined        ","option5":"None of these        ","correct_option":"900","qa_date":"2016-05-10 00:53:58","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>60% marks = 540<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>100% marks = <sup>540&times;100<\/sup>\/<sub>60 <\/sub>= 900<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6388","question":"<p>A committee of 3 members is to be formed out of 3 men and 4 women. In who many different ways can it be done so that at least one member is a woman?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"34","option2":"12","option3":"30","option4":"36","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"34","qa_date":"2016-05-07 05:59:05","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>The committee can be formed in the following ways :<\/p>\r\n\r\n<ol style=\"list-style-type:lower-roman\">\r\n\t<li>By selecting 2 men and 1 women<\/li>\r\n\t<li>By selecting 1 men and 2 women<\/li>\r\n\t<li>By selecting&nbsp; 3 women<\/li>\r\n<\/ol>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.5in\">&nbsp;Total number of ways of forming the committee<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.5in\">= 3c<sub>2 <\/sub>&times; 4c<sub>1 <\/sub>+3c<sub>1 <\/sub>&times; 4c<sub>2 <\/sub>+ 3c<sub>3<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.5in\">= 3 &times; 4 + 3 &times; 6 + 4<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.5in\">= 12 + 18 + 4&nbsp; = 34<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6382","question":"<p>210&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 209&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 213&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 186&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 202&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; (?)&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"139","option2":"77","option3":"177","option4":"327","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"77","qa_date":"2016-05-07 05:21:19","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>The pattern of the number series is :<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">210 &ndash; 1<sup>3<\/sup> = 209<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">209 + 2<sup>2<\/sup> = 213<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">213 &ndash; 3<sup>3<\/sup> = 186<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">186 + 4<sup>2<\/sup> = 202<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">202 &ndash; 5<sup>3<\/sup> = 202 &ndash; 125 = <strong>[77]<\/strong><\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6387","question":"<p>In a two digit number the digit in the unit&rsquo;s place is twice the digit in the ten&rsquo;s place is twice the digit in the ten&rsquo;s place and the number obtained by interchanging the digits is more than the original number by 27. What is 50% of the original number?&nbsp;<\/p>\r\n","option1":"36","option2":"63","option3":"48","option4":"18","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"36","qa_date":"2016-05-07 05:50:11","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Let the ten&rsquo;s digit be x.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">Unit&rsquo;s digit = 2x<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">Original number =10x + 2x = 12x<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">On interchanging the digits, the new number = 10 &times; 2x + x = 21x<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">According to question,<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">21x &ndash; 12x = 27 &rarr; 9x = 27<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">&rarr; x = <sup>27<\/sup>\/<sub>9 <\/sub>= 3<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">Original number = 12x<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">=12 &times; 3 = 36.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6391","question":"<p>The salary of an employee increases consistently by 50% every year.&nbsp; If his salary today is Rs. 10,000, what will be the salary after another 4 years?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"Rs. 62,500","option2":"Rs. 26,500","option3":"Rs. 50,625","option4":"Rs. 33,750","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"Rs. 50,625","qa_date":"2016-05-07 05:59:05","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Required salary<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">= 10000 (1 + <sup>50 <\/sup>\/<sub>100<\/sub>) <sup>4<\/sup><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p style=\"margin-left:1.0in\">= 10000 &times; (1.5)<sup>4<\/sup> = Rs. 50625<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6403","question":"<p>Find the average of the following set of scores.<\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; 216,&nbsp; 463, 154,&nbsp; 605,&nbsp; 446,&nbsp; 336<\/p>\r\n","option1":"387","option2":"370","option3":"379 ","option4":"380","option5":"None of these       ","correct_option":"370","qa_date":"2016-05-09 04:00:40","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":"<p>Required average = <sup>addition of all six numbers<\/sup>\/<sub>6<\/sub><\/p>\r\n\r\n<p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp; = <sup>2220<\/sup>\/<sub>6<\/sub> = 370.<\/p>\r\n"},{"id":"6366","question":"<p>Which of the following sentences should be the second after rearrangement?<\/p>\r\n","option1":"A","option2":"B","option3":"C","option4":"E","option5":"F","correct_option":"E","qa_date":"2016-05-06 11:55:16","section_description":"","max_marks":"1","answer":""}]